Current Address: Doha, Qatar Email: Engahmed\_ameen@hotmail.com

Professional: Senior Planning Engineer Mobile: +974 55 205024

### **CAREER OBJECTIVE**

A highly successful senior planner with six years' experience in construction project management, planning, scheduling, project monitoring & controlling by using earned value technique and delay analysis & extension of time. Seeking a private role in a well-established, growth driven organization which will add to my career, sharpen my skills and make me able to add new ideas and contribute in the company success. In addition, I will do my best to achieve high productivity for the tasks under my responsibility to fulfill the organization target, requirements and to satisfy both of clients as well as the top management.



#### Area of Expertise

- Planning & Scheduling Professional (PSP).
- Project Management Professional (PMP).
- Earned Value Management.
- Delay Analysis & Extension of Time.
- Tendering & Construction Stage.
- Construction of mega & mixed residential buildings, malls, high rise buildings, international standard of schools, hospitals and factories projects in Qatar, Saudi Arabia & Egypt.

#### **ACADEMIC EDUCATION**

# Faculty of Engineering, Zagazig University, Egypt

Bachelor's degree in Civil Engineering

- Total Graduation Grade: Good 73.04%
- Graduation Project: Construction Project Management, Grade: Excellent

# Arab Academy for Science Technology and Maritime Transport, Egypt

Preparation Courses of Master Degree in Construction Project Management:

- Advanced Construction Management.
- Advanced Construction Engineering.
- Value Engineering in Construction Industry.
- Financial Management in Construction.
- Advanced Equipment Management.
- Project Planning and Control.

# **PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATES**

**AACE International**, United States

Planning and Scheduling Professional (PSP), Certified No. 1238

April 2013

Jun 2008

Sep 2009 - Jun 2010

# Other Trainings and Certifications:

- Oct 2013: IELTS preparation course, Expression English Training Center-Qatar.
- Jul 2013: PMP (Project Management Professional) preparation course, Madras Training & Management Institute-Qatar.
- Nov 2012: Leadership Skills course, AL-Habtoor Leighton Group-Qatar.
- Apr 2012: PSP (Planning and Scheduling Professional) preparation course, CMCS-Qatar.
- May 2011: Planning & scheduling by using Primavera Oracle P6 certified from Oracle, CMCS-Egypt.
- Sep 2009: Preparation course for IPMA certificate, Talaat Moustafa Group-Egypt.

# **SKILLS**

- Strong management skills, Positive attitude, self-motivated, proactive, resourceful, undertaking responsibilities.
- Capable of hands on problem-solving, with ability to generate ideas and solutions.
- Strong communication skills in all forms including written, oral, email, telephone and presentation.
- Capable of working independently, and having responsibility to work as an individual and in team work.
- Computer Skills: Primavera (P3, 6.7 & P6 R8.3), AutoCAD 2d, MS Office, Sap2000, Document Control Soft wares (Wrench & Docwize) & Internet with using all different types of windows.

#### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

Stefanutti Stocks Company, Qatar Senior Planning Engineer Sep 2013 - Present

# **Key Tender Projects:**

- American School of Doha (tender & contract programme).
- Aquatic Fisheries & Research Center.
- Hamad Hospital Simulation Center.
- Qatar University & Al-Waab Healthcare Centers.
- Arab Center for Research & Policy Studies.
- JW Marriott Hotel Tower.

# Ahmed El-Sayed Amin Moustafa, PSP

Current Address: Doha, Qatar Email: Engahmed\_ameen@hotmail.com

Professional: Senior Planning Engineer Mobile: +974 55 205024

#### **Key Responsibilities:**

- Preparation of tender programmes.
- Preparation of master, detailed, recovery, accelerated plans and short term programmes.
- Preparation of project organization chart related to project schedule.
- Preparation of resources and cost loaded planning schedules.
- Preparation of resource histograms for manpower & material and project s-curves.
- Produce weekly & monthly KPI's.
- Manage subcontractor's schedule in line with the baseline schedule.
- Schedule weekly & monthly updates.
- Weekly progress monitoring & actual productivity reports.
- Provide actual progress status and forecast by using earned value technique.
- Provide recommendations when actual progress deviates from scheduled programme in order to re-align to on time completion.
- Preparation of delay analysis and extension of time by using time impact analysis.
- At the completion of the project, assists in developing and recording the project's historical schedule information and "lessons learned", for use on future enterprise projects.

# AL-Habtoor Leighton Group, Qatar Project Planning Engineer

Jun 2011 - Aug 2013

#### **Kev Projects:**

North Gate Mall & Office Buildings Phase I, Doha-Qatar.

North Gate is a mixed-use development in a growing neighborhood on one of Doha's strategically important arterial roadways, Al Shamal Road (North Road), north of Doha's West Bay central business district. The total built-up area of around is 375,000 square meters, with a podium comprising two levels of car park, a three-level mall and six, five-level office buildings. Contract Value is QR 1.32 Billion equal to \$362 Million.

#### **Key Responsibilities:**

- Preparation of master, detailed, recovery, accelerated plans and short term programmes.
- Preparation of resources and cost loaded planning schedules.
- Preparation of resource histograms for manpower & material and project s-curves.
- Produce weekly & monthly KPI's.
- Manage subcontractor's schedule in line with the baseline schedule.
- Schedule weekly & monthly updates.
- Weekly progress monitoring & actual productivity reports.
- Provide actual progress status and forecast by using earned value technique.
- Provide recommendations when actual progress deviates from scheduled programme in order to re-align to on time completion.
- Preparation of delay analysis and extension of time by using time impact analysis.

# CMCS - Collaboration Management & Control Solutions, Project Management Co., Egypt Jun 2010 - May 2011 Planning Engineer

# **Key Projects:**

King Khalid University-Male Academic Campus, Abha-Saudi Arabia.

The contract included 16 new buildings and their annexes, consisting of engineering and science and administrative buildings over a 36-months period. Contract Value is SR 2,296,506,869.97 equal to \$630 Million.

#### **Key Responsibilities:**

- Assist in preparing of master and detailed plans.
- Prepare of resource and cost loaded planning schedules.
- Produce resource histograms for manpower and material.
- Schedule weekly monitoring and updating.
- Provide actual progress status and forecast.
- Organize and manage actual work on site in order to meet programmes and quality standards.
- Review specifications and drawings in order to resolve and discrepancies or conflicts.

# Talaat Moustafa Group (Alex. construction Co.), Egypt Site Engineer

Jul 2008 - May 2010

# **Key Projects:**

British International School, Madinaty-Egypt.

British International School in Madinaty is offering world-class education to children from preschool to primary year four in an environment conducive to learning and growth. The school's state-of-the-art facilities include air-conditioned classrooms, a large swimming pool, Labs, Sports hall, sports fields and a multipurpose hall. The school was constructed on total land area of 7,031 m2 and comprises 36 classes distributed on four floors (Ground floor 6,399 m2, first floor 5,063 m2, second floor 5,237 m2 and third floor 1879 m2) in additional to 240 m2 playground. Contract Value is L.E 150 Million equal to \$25 Million.

# Ahmed El-Sayed Amin Moustafa, PSP

Current Address: Doha, Qatar Email: Engahmed\_ameen@hotmail.com

Professional: Senior Planning Engineer Mobile: +974 55 205024

#### **Key Responsibilities:**

- Prepare construction programme and follow up it.
- Carry out the work based on approved drawings and method statement with objective of ensuring the desired quality.
- Review drawings and look ahead programmes for any technical discrepancy.
- Ensure quality and safety is maintained at the highest standard.
- Review specifications.
- Ensure good housekeeping and follow all safety regulations.
- Checks work progress as against daily, weekly and monthly targets.
- Provide update and feedback on matters concerning the increase and decrease of labour force during manpower schedule.
- Ensure and optimize appropriate movement and utilization of materials.
- Coordinate the scheduling of the foremen's activities in accordance with the construction programme.
- Review the subcontractor's drawings and project plans.
- Ensure proper execution of subcontractors works accordingly.

# **PERSONAL INFORMATION**

Name : Ahmed EL-Sayed Amin Moustafa

Birth Date : 29 September 1986

Gender : MaleNationality : Egypt

Visa Status : Residency Visa
Residence Location: Doha, Qatar
Marital Status : Married + 1 daughter
Driving License : Egypt & Qatar
Military Status : Exempted

# **MEMBERSHIPS**

- Member in Egyptian Engineers Syndicate since July 2008.
- Member of AACE International since Apr 2013.

# **LANGUAGES**

- Arabic: Native language.
- English: Very good (speaking, reading & writing).

# **REFRENCES**

Available upon request.